Email: bashir.zuhair@gmail.com Tripoli, Libya +218910018987 / +218915677567

Professional Summary

Experienced Information Technology Assistant with over 10 years of experience in IT and Communication roles, particularly with programming sector. Skilled in the development and operation of information systems, electronic data processing, computer system architecture, and data analysis.

Education

 Master of Science in Procurement, Logistics, and Supply Chain Management University of Salford, Manchester, UK

Date: 24 July 2023 - 06 February 2024

 Bachelor in Electrical Engineering Al-Fateh University, Tripoli, Libya Conferral Date: 18 February 2015

• Certificate in SQL Server

The Professional Programmer Company, Tripoli, Libya

Conferral Date: 18 December 2016

Skills

- Data Management & Analysis: Expertise in ERP systems (SAP), Power BI, SQL databases, data visualization, and reporting.
- Property Management: Proficient in asset management, inventory control, property inspections, and compliance with UN policies.
- IT Skills: Proficient in C#, ASP.NET, VB.NET, SQL, PHP, HTML. Experience with CISCO switches and routers.
- Process Improvement: Implemented standard operating procedures and preventive maintenance schedules.
- Cross-Functional Collaboration: Experience working with cross-functional teams to achieve organizational goals.

Professional Experience

Almotakamel Company

Database Administrator Nov 2017 - May 2018

- Developed web applications and managed SQL server applications.
- Designed ERP systems for the Libyan Ministry of Health, using Visual Studio platform.

Zajel Libya for Telecom & Technology Company

Logistics Assistant

Basheer Zuhayr Basheer Alhafi

08 November 1988

Email: bashir.zuhair@gmail.com Tripoli, Libya +218910018987 / +218915677567

Jan 2016 - Oct 2017

- Managed vendor negotiations and equipment maintenance.
- Migrated data systems from Excel to SQL server databases.

WAVE Company (Subcontract of ZTE Company)

Telecommunication Engineer Sep 2014 - Jan 2016

- Led field teams for maintenance and installation of LIBYANA towers.
- Managed property inspections and updates using SQL server.
- Managed network operations and client support.

Fourth Dimension Company

Database Administrator Feb 2010 - Sep 2014

- Built ERP systems using C#, SQL server databases.
- Designed multi-threaded applications and developed websites using PHP and HTML.

Languages

Arabic: NativeEnglish: Fluent